SAMUEL HONG

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

(785) 375-2086

hongssam9@gmail.com

in https://www.linkedin.com/in/hongssam9/

https://github.com/hongssam9



SUMMARY

An ambitious software engineering fellow with a mechanical engineering background with a track record for providing reliable technical expertise, project management, and program delivery. An innovator who excels in the challenge of accurate solutions for difficult situations in product design, testing, and development. A well-rounded and reliable leader with outstanding interpersonal and communication skills, driven to develop and grow within a challenging and rewarding career and work environment.

SKILLS

Programming Languages JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, MATLAB, C++, Java, LabVIEW

Framework & Libraries React, Django

Databases MongoDB, SQL, PostgreSQL

Platforms SolidWorks (CAD), Patran/Nastran, Microsoft Office

Miscellaneous GD&T, Research and Testing, Stress and Strain Analysis, Thermodynamics and Mechanics,

Finite Element Analysis (FEA)

Languages English, Korean, Spanish

EXPERIENCE

Software Engineering Fellow

Oct 2021 - Current

General Assembly

500+ hours of intensive training in a variety of modern programming languages and technologies

 Produced four web applications using full-stack JavaScript and several other programming languages

Direct Methanol Fuel Cell Research · Co-Leader

lan 2019 - Dec 2019

University of Kansas

Investigated the use and impact of direct methanol fuel cells in material handling applications

- Developed and tested methods to increase performance and decrease costs of direct methanol fuel cells
- Planned, scheduled, and aligned personnel, project testing resources to ensure reliable results

Dilatant Decelerate System · Project Leader

Jan 2019 - May 2019

University of Kansas

Responsible for redesigning US Air Force helmets to reduce whiplash and augment safety and function

- Constructed and tested 30 prototypes to ensure quality and reliability while not compromising functionality
- Successfully reinforced helmet base plate to allow full lateral head movement by 35%

EDUCATION

General Assembly

Oct 2021 - Current

Software Engineering Immersive

University of Kansas

Aug 2014 - Dec 2019

B.S. Mechanical Engineering (BSME)